A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Jamaica and Mexico City Field Office Files FA612
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John S. Nagel (LAC Representative) Desk Files, 1966-1973; II
  - Rome -- April Marino Conference 1970 and Additional Population Evaluation Program Materials, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
  - Tax Reform Act (H.R. 13270), 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Trips -- Bundy-Miller Visits to Latin America, Oct-Nov 1970 (Box 2)
  - Trips -- Visit of Mr. and Mrs. Miller to Latin America, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Trips -- Mr. Bell's Trip to Venezuela and Colombia, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Urbanization Survey -- Robin, John P., 1970-1971 (Box 2)
- Reports, 1958-1969; III
  - Argentina -- "Exploratory Mission to Latin America: Argentina" by Alfred Wolf, Reynold Carlson, Lincoln Gordon, Kalman Silvert, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Notes on Argentina" by Robert Alexander -- Re: Politics, Feb 1959 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Government of the University of Buenos Aires" by Kalman H. Silvert, Nov 1959 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Ford Foundation Mission to Argentina, Aug-Sep 1959, Summary of Recommendations", Mar 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Trip Notes, Argentina" by Alfred C. Wolf and Reynold Carlson, Jul 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Notes on Visit to Buenos Aires", Jul-Aug 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Notes on Argentina and Peru -- Related to Dean Harrison's Argentina Visit, Aug 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Suggestions for Ford Foundation Support of Science and Technology in Argentina (Report of a Visit to Argentina in July-August 1960)" by C.V. Kidd, Sep 15, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Basic Science in Argentina, Mid 1960" by George R. Harrison, Sep 28, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Trip Report, Sep-Oct 1960 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Manpower Survey Prepared for the Instituto Torcuato di Tella" by Robert L. Thomas, Jan 1961 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "The Availability of Economists in the United Kingdom and France for Service Overseas" by Jo W. Saxe, Aug 2, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Education in the Field of Economic Development and Administration in Argentina and Chile" by William D. Carmichael, Nov 1963 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Library of Faculty of Exact and Natural Sciences at the University of Buenos Aires -- Two Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "University of Buenos Aires, School of Economics (Grant 62-235)" Memo from William D. Carmichael, Apr 2, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Economics in Argentina" by William D. Carmichael and Joseph Grunwald, Jun 1965 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Visit to Argentina, March-April 1967 -- Cotton, Albert, Apr 1967 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Visit to Argentina, May 7th through May 19th, 1967" Memo from Abraham S. Fischler, May 29, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Bariloche Report" by Thomas P. Nickell, Jr., Jun 26, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "General Reflections on a Visit to Argentina" by Richard N. Adams -- Re: Sociology and Anthropology, Sep 1, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Notes on Brazil" by Robert Alexander, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Exploratory Mission to Latin America - Brazil, 1959" by Alfred Wolf, Reynold Carlson, Lincoln Gordon (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Discussions on Brazil Held at Various U.S. Government Agencies, March 16-20, 1959" Memo from Nita Rous Manitzas, Mar 23, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Recommendations to Ford Foundation for Support of Economic Research Programs in Brazil" by Alfred C. Neal and Reynold E. Carlson, Apr 29, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Economic Growth in Brazil" by Reynold E. Carlson, May 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Ford Foundation Mission to Brazil, Summary of Recommendations" by Alfred Wolf, Lincoln Gordon, and Reynold Carlson, Aug 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "The Current Economic Situation in Brazil" by Reynold Carlson, Dec 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "American Cooperation with Brazilian Universities" by Robert J. Havighurst, Apr 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- Memorandum Re: Aeronautical Technicological Institute from E.E. Hagen, Jun 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Trip Notes, Brazil" by Alfred C. Wolf and Reynold Carlson, Jul 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Economics Teaching and Training of Economists in Brazil - An Appraisal with Recommendations" by Everett E. Hagen and William H. Nicholls, Jul 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Secondary Science Education in Brazil" by Karl Dittmer, Paul Klinge, and Arthur Roe, Jul 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Summary Report on Visit to Brazil -- Part A, Observations and Recommendations with Respect to Labor Market Research in Brazil" by C.V. Kidd, Sep 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Summary Report on Visit to Brazil -- Part B, Observations and Recommendations with Respect to Support of Science in Brazil" by C.V. Kidd, Sep 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- Correspondence Re: Visits to Science Centers from L. Grinter, Sep 6, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "A Report on a General Survey of the Libraries of the University of Sao Paulo" by Herman H. Fussler and Supplementary Statement, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Organizational Outline of the Proposed Institute of Statistics at the University of Sao Paulo" by Jerzy Neyman, Mar-Apr 1961 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Notes on the Brazil Grant Program" by Sidney Mintz, Jun 1961 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Basic Science in Brazil, Mid 1961" by George R. Harrison, Sep 1, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Observations upon Visits to Science Centers in Brazil, August 1962" by Charles V. Kidd, Sep 1962 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "An Integrated Plan for Strengthening Graduate Education in Brazil" by Charles V. Kidd (confidential draft of a proposal), Sep 12, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report of the Ford Foundation Survey Team on Pulic Administration Teaching and Research in Brazil" by Frederic N. Cleaveland, May 31, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on a Request for a Grant to Strengthen Graudate Education in the Sciences Throughout Brazil" by Charles V. Kidd, Jul 31, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on Mission to Survey Present Activities and Future Possibilities of ETV in Brazil" by James W. Armsey and John F. Baxter, Aug 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Instituto de Economia Rural Universidade Rural do Estado de Minas Gerais Vicosa, Minas Gerais, Brazil -- Current Status and Prospects" -- Progress Report by D. Woods Thomas, Aug 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Graduate Teaching and Research in Economics", Sep 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on the Rural University of the State of Minas Gerais", Oct 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Introductory Report on Brazilian Education with Special Reference to Secondary Schools" by George F.G. Little, Mar 1964 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "A Study of Technical Education Problems in Brazil" by Ernest J. Simon, Albert E. French, Henry P. Adams, Aug 30, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on Trip to Brazil: August 2-September 3, 1964" by Nicholas Georgescu-Roegen, Sep 1964 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "An Appraisal of the Needs of the Universidade Rural do Estado de Minas Gerais - Supplement 1", Dec 12, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Sao Paulo University CCTV Consultation Report" by Kenneth Christianson, Dec 15, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Activity Report of Ford Foundation Consultant to Advise on the Development of Post-Colegio Technical Education in Brazil" Memo from Henry P. Adams, Apr 12, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Political Science: Public Administration and Development in Brazil" by Peter Bell, Sep 1965 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report to the Ford Foundation on Support for Graduate Study in Science at the University of Brazil" by George R. Harrison, Dec 1, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Evaluation of the IRI Research Institute Animal Nutrition Center Program in Brazil and Related Agricultural Research and Educational Institutions" by Kenneth L. Turk, Jan 21, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on Visit to Rio de Janeiro to Explore Research Possibilities with BNDE and Sao Paulo School of Business Administration" by J.D. Nyhart, Mar 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Comments on Visit to Escola Americana, Rio de Janeiro, at the Request of the Ford Foundation" Memo from James D. MacConnell, Apr 5, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Notes on Engineering Education in Brazil" Memo from K.N. Rao, May 11, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "A Suggested Program of BNDE-MIT Cooperation in Research and Management Training in the Brazilian National Development Banking System" and Related Correspondence, Jul 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report of the Inter-American Development Bank Mission to Brazil" by Reuben Frodin, Charles F. Gosnell, K.N. Rao (English and Portuguese) and Related Documents, Jul-Sep 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas Letter Re: Visit about Vargas Support, Jul 3, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "The French Caribbean" by Richard M. Morse, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Report Re: Visit to Trinidad and Tobago and West Indies Information Sheets (report missing), [1959] (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Haiti Trip Report by Sidney Mintz, Feb 1959 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "University of Puerto Rico - Natural Sciences and Agriculture" by Paul Pearson, Mar 8, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Report of Activities in Connection with Santo Domingo Project for a Post-High School Business Institute" by Hamden L. Forkner, Oct 6, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Report on Visit to Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic in Connection with Possible Support of APEC Plans for a Junior College of Business by Lionel H. Mercier, Oct 8, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Structures and Processes for Biomedical Research Policy in the British Caribbean" by C.V. Kidd, May 3, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "The Political Situation in the Dominican Republic" by Robert A. Mayer, Sep 10, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Institute of Advanced Studies (ISA) Curriculum Development and Teacher Training" by Amalia Llabres de Charneco, Nov 30, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Trip to Dominican Republic, March 25-April 1, 1966" Memorandum from Morris A. Horowitz, Apr 12, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "The Dominican Crisis of 1965: An Annotated Bibilography" by Abraham Lowenthal, Jun 1967 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Report Re: Jamaica Visit by Amos H. Hawley, Feb 1969 (Box 3)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "A Report to the Ford Foundation Concerning Program Possibilities in Latin America" by the Yale Group, Jun 10, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Economic Research and Training in Latin America" by Richard Ruggles and Nancy Ruggles, Mar 1960 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Basic Science in Central America (Early 1962)" by George R. Harrison, May 1962 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Observations on Pan American School of Agriculture" by William K. Gamble, Dec 1962 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "University Education and the Regional Concept in Central America" by Harold L. Enarson, Aug 1963 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Human Resources Study of Central America, An Interim Report" by Herbert J. Betz, Sep 1963 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Two Reports Re: Latin American Studies in the United States by Carl B. Spaeth (one co-written by John B. Howard), 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Grants to National Universities of Honduras and Nicaragua, Feb 1965 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Memorandum Re: Seminar on Population Problems, Mar 23, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Representatives Conference, Princeton -- Re: International Development, Development of the Social Sciences, and Training and Employment of "Middle Level" Technicians, Nov 1965 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Toward Strategies for Public Administration Development in Latin America" by John C. Honey, Mar 1966 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Agricultural Development in Latin America" Statement by Lowell S. Hardin before the International Finance Sub-Committee, House of Representatives, Aug 29, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Urban Planning and Development Centers in Latin America" by Guido G. Weigund and James H. Street, Apr 1967 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "University Libraries - Appendix D - The Questionnaire to University Libraries" by Paul Bixler, Jun 1967 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "The Challenge - A Political Economist's Views" by Byron L. Johnson -- Conference Paper, Aug-Sep 1967 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "The Role of the Humanities in Desarrollo: The Latin American Case" by William L. Reese, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Possibilities for Significant Studies of Land Reform in Chile" by Marion Clawson, Apr 1960 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Correspondence/Report Re: Education Planning Committee from Paul Bulger, Oct 21, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "A Report on Chilean Agriculture and Agricultural Education to the Ford Foundation" by S.O. Berg, L.E. Hanson, W.P. Martin, Nov 1963 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Memorandum, Chile Education Planning Committee Re: Visit to Santiago, Apr 3, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Report Re: Library Development at University of Concepcion by E.W. McDiarmid, Apr 29, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Community Facilities Project in Chile (published booklet), Feb 1966 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Correspondence/Report Re: Urban Development Advisory Program, Jan 10, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "School of Business, Catholic University, Valparaiso", May 15, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Consultant's Report Re: Education, "Project in Curricular Reform and Teaching Retraining" by Michael Chiappetta, May-Jun 1967 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Trip Report for a Study of the Chemical Engineering Program at the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria" by John W. Tierney, Sep 6, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Memorandum Re: Chile and Urban and Regional Planning from Ralph A. Gakenheimer, Sep 13, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Trip Report for a Study of the Electrical Engineering Program at the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria" by Howard B. Hamilton, Sep 28, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Trip Report - A Study of Engineering Programs at the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria" by H.E. Hoelscher, Oct 19, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Ford Foundation Mission to Colombia" by Richard Morse, Robert Wickham, Alfred Wolf, Jun 1960 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Political and Economic Profile of Colombia - Ford Foundation Mission to Colombia" by Richard Morse, Robert Wickham, Alfred Wolf, Jun 1960 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Manpower Problems and Policies in Colombia" by J.F. Wellemeyer (draft and final copies included), Dec 1960-Jan 1961 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Colombia - Martin Kriesberg's Role" by George A. Graham, 1962 August 27 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Report to the Ford Foundation Concerning the Developments and Prospects at the University of Antioquia, Medellin, Colombia" by Francic T. Bonner, Sidney Gelber, Richard M. Morse, Apr 1963 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "The Armsey-Morrill Mission to the Universidad del Valle, Cali, Colombia" Memo from J.L. Morrill, Aug 12, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Review of Agricultural Progress in Colombia" by Robert Wickham, [1964] (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "ICA's Current Program in Colombia and Possible Areas Where the Ford Foundation Might Render Meaningful Assistance" Memo from J. Norman Efferson, Jul 24, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Report to the [Ford] Foundation on Consultation with the University of the Andes, Bogota, Colombia" by James S. Triolo, Sep 21, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Review of Colombian Population Program Developments since November 12, 1964 and Projections until Summer 1966" by Dieter Zschock, Jul 1, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Progress Report on the Development Program of the University of the Andes, Bogota, March 20-23, 1966" by James S. Triolo, Mar 1966 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Trip Report" by John M. Hunter, Dec 1966 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Report on a Trip to Bogota and Cali" by Arthur J. Coutu, Mar 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Confidential Report of Visit to Colombia, March 17-April 3, 1967 to Study the Development of Selected University Faculties of Education" by Robert N. Bush, Apr 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- Correspondence Re: University of Valle, Javeriana, Antioquia from H. Thomas James, Apr 13, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Universidad Nacional - Consultation Visit Concerning Centralized Cataloging in the Libraries" by Imogene Hixson, Jul 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "The Faculty of Human Sciences National University of Colombia" by William D. Carmichael and Peter D. Bell, Jul 17, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- University of Antioquia -- Library Development, Sep 25, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Costa Rica -- "Faculty of Agronomy, University of Costa Rica, Report on Visit to the Faculty" by William K. Gamble, Nov 13, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Costa Rica -- "Report on a Project to Expand Economic Research and Improve the Training of Economists at the University of Costa Rica" by Victor L. Urquidi, Mar 1963 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Report on the Proposed Integrated Agricultural Institute at Chapingo, Mexico", Jul 1962 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Agricultural Program" by J.S. Nagel, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Comments and Recommendations on the Agricultural Economics Center" by Earl O. Heady, Apr 1964 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "A Study and Evaluation - State of Mexico Agricultural Extension Service", Oct 1964 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Progress Report Number Three on Study and Evaluation Recommendations", Feb 11, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Program for the Centro Nacional de Productividad in Management Development and Organization Improvement in Industrial Enterprises" by Emmett Wallace, Dec 2, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- Correspondence Re: Ford Foundation Mission to Mexico, Dec 27, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Graduate Education in Management at UNAM (National Autonomous University of Mexico)" by William D. Carmichael, Richard M. Cyert, Ezra Solomon, Feb 20, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- Report Re: Mexican Institute of Social Studies by Reuben Hill, Mar 17, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- Trip Report by Bernard P. Queenan, Jun 10, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Notes on Mexican Visit" Re: Anthropology, Sep 1967 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "The Mexican Library" and Related Correspondence/Letter of Transmittal by Paul Bixler, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Library and Information Services in Mexico" by Carl M. White, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: National Engineering University, Apr 19, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- "The Program in Peru - Report on its Current Status" by Peter Fraenkel, Jan 8, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: Population Development in Peru, Mar 1965 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- "Report to the Ford Foundation, Evaluation of and Recommendation for the Faculty of Engineering at the Catholic University of Peru" by Sidney A. Guralnick, Jul 19, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- "Suggestions Concerning Agricultural Budgeting and Programming in Peru" by L.S. Hardin and F.F. Hill, May 30, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: Lima Visit and Education (May 16-17, 1967) by Bernard P. Queenan, Jun 5, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: Visit to Study Inter-University Council by Herman B. Wells, Aug 17, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Venezuela Report" by R.S. Wickham, May 1962 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Record of Conversation with Dr. Aristides Calvani of Universidad Catolica Andres Bello -- Conversation Reports and Suggestions, Jul 1962 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Report Re: Educational Planning by O.M. Wilson, Sep 9, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Seminar on Educational Planning, August 3-7, 1964, Caracas, Venezuela" Memo by Harold W. Stoke, Aug 12, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Report Re: Establishment of Post-Graduate Institute of Administration, Jul 1964 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Evaluation of Universidad de Oriente Possibilities to Develop Eastern Venezuela" by Antonio Bacigalupo, Sep 1964 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Trip Report (Aug 25-Sep 2, 1964) and Universidad de Oriente by Grover E. Murray, Oct 26, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Correspondence/Report Re: Science Project/Oriente-Kansas by B. Leonard, Jun 23, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Report on Consultation with EDUPLAN and Ford Foundation Personnel" by Frederick B. Davis, Aug 1967 (Box 4)
  - "Written Testimony for the Subcommittee on Government Research of the Committee on Government Operations, United States Senate" by K.H. Silvert, Jun 27, 1967 (Box 4)
- Subject Files, 1963-1973; IV
  - Administration -- Establishment of Ford Foundation Office in Kingston -- Legal Status, 1964-1970 (Box 5)
  - Administration -- Establishment of Office in Kingston, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
  - Administration -- Ford Foundation, New York -- Insurance Coverage -- Fire, Theft, Accidents, 1966-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Antigua -- General, incl. Donald David's Antigua Speech, 1965-1971 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Bahamas -- General, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Black Power, Studies, and Race Relations, 1969-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- British Ministry of Overseas Development (MOD), 1967-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Caribbean Food and Nutrition Institute (CFNI), 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- CARIFTA -- Reports, [1969], n.d. (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- CARIFTA, 1967-1971 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Conservation -- Caribbean Conservation Association, incl. booklet on Ford Foundation Grants in Resources and Environment, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Cuba -- Research on Lower-Class Families in Cuba -- Supplement No. 1, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Educational Television -- General, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Ford Foundation Caribbean Program -- Project Data Sheets Binder, Oct 1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Ford Foundation Contributions in Education and Manpower Development, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Marine Sciences, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Organization of Caribbean Bar Association, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Regional Development Bank, 1968-1973 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- University of the Netherland Antilles, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Caribbean -- Vocational Education in Eastern Caribbean -- MOD Proposal (L67-447), 1967-1972 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Association for Development -- General, 1966-1970 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Dominican Fellows Program, 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Ford Foundation Dominican Agricultural Program, 1964-1969 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- Fundacion Dominicana de Desarrollo (FDD), 1969-1972 (Box 5)
  - Dominican Republic -- General, 1964-1970 (Box 6)
  - Dominican Republic -- Political Situation Reports, 1964-1970 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- Agricultural Program, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- General, 1966-1972 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- Individual Studies/Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - Haiti -- Social Sciences -- CHISS -- General and Publication, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Grenada -- General, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Guyana -- University of Guyana -- English Dialect Survey Discretionary Project, 1967-1971 (Box 6)
  - Guyana -- Report on Education in Guyana, Nov 1967 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Archaeology and Conservation, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- "Brain Drain" study (Jay Buffenmeyer), 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Central Planning Unit, 1966-1972 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Citizens Education Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Conference on Education, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Consultant Report Re: Industrial Relations System and Jamaica Employers' Federation, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Institute of Management, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Jamaica -- Library Issues Re: UWI and Ford Foundation Field Office, 1963-1968 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Manley Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Ministry of Finance and Planning, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Ministry of Youth and Development, 1967-1971 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Parliamentary Library Proposal and Support, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- Scientific Research Council and Report Re: Science Policy in Venezuela, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Jamaica -- U.S. Embassy and Aid, 1965-1971 (Box 7)